So now I'll say, well,
what if I wanted--
and remember, these are forming
these long, viscous chains.
What if I wanted to make them
flow a little more easily?
What if I wanted them
to form shorter chains?
What if I wanted
to cut the pasta?
Don't do it in Italy.
They'll get really upset.
But Americans are OK with it.
If you need to cut the pasta,
it's OK in this country.
But if I need to cut the pasta
in chemistry and it's glass
that I'm cutting,
O2- is my knife.
It's my chemical scissors.
Chemical scissors, I like
that-- chemical scissors.
Why?
Well, you can see
because I go back.
What did the oxygen do?
By bridging it didn't
need that extra electron.
But if I bring now
something like Na2O--
so I've got an O2-.
Now I'm going to add an O2-.
Then what will happen is
you're going to cut this.
So now I'll just draw the--
I'll see if I can--
OK, so now I've added not just
an oxygen atom but the two
charges that each of them needed
before they bridged, you see,
to be happy?
And so now this can have
one of those charges,
and over here you
can have another one,
and so on and so on.
But see, now I've cut.
I've cut the glass pasta,
and I've done it chemically
and I've done it
from understanding
of octet and Lewis,
from basic chemistry
principles that we've learned.